www.linkedin.com/in/sara-munir in





sara.m07011@gmail.com

www.saramunir.com

+1 437 984 6134

Toronto, Canada

ABOUT ME

I am a Front End Web developer with experience in building applications with React, Javascript (vanilla & ES6+), HTML5, CSS3, Nodejs, MySql, MongoDb and API integration.

My training so far has equiped me with a strong sense of complex yet creative problem solving skills. Due to my background in architecture i have developed expertise in visual design elements such as color, typography and layout.

With years of training, i have grown to be strong systematic thinker, that allows me to focus on figuring out the big pictures before jumping into the details.

SKILLS

Languages & Databases:

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, MySQL, NoSQL (MongoDB), FireBase

Frameworks & Libraries:

Node (Express), React, Mongoose, Bootstrap, jQuery, Bootstrap

Other:

Git, RESTful APIs, Heroku, Adobe, Photoshop, Adobe illustrator, Autocad, 3dMax, PhotoPea, Jira, Salesforce, Team player, successful communicator

EDUCATION

Wev Development Immersive

Juno College of Technology 2021, Toronto, Canada

Full Stack Web Flex Course

School of Continuing Studies, University of Torontoy 2020, Toronto, Canada

Bachelor of Architecture

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology 2013, Dhaka, Bangladesh

PROJECTS

Thought Escape

REACT | CSS | JAVASCRIPT | FIREBASE

A social media application based of facebook/twitter that allows a user to share their thoughts. Users can follow other users and comment and like thoughts they have posted.

Live: https://objective-heisenberg-ab7d8c.netlify.app/

GitHub: https://github.com/SaraMunir/sara-munir-juno-project3

SARA MUNIR

Sun Run

REACT | CSS | JAVASCRIPT | FIREBASE | API

A fitness web application that allows users to plan their runs based on the sunlight. User can select if they want to hit sunrise or sunset and plan their runs accordingly.

Live: https://sunrun.netlify.app/

GitHub: https://github.com/Chimbuken/sun-run

Movie Maniax

REACT | CSS | NODE JS | MONGO DB | BOOTSTRAP | API

Movie Maniax is a user-friendly movie search application built on MERN stack that allows users to search for movies, add movies to watchlist as well as to favorites list. Users can also add other users as their friend and view their favourite list, watchlist and reviews.

Live: https://movie-maniax.herokuapp.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/jsanthos01/MovieManiax

A Game Of Thrones Trivia

HTML5 | CSS | SCSS | JAVASCRIPT | API

A Web based quiz/trivia based on the very popular tv show Game Of Thrones quotes. Random quotes from the tv show is generated for the user where they have to guess who said the quote.

Live: https://movie-maniax.herokuapp.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/jsanthos01/MovieManiax

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

ABON PHARMACEUTICALS | Remote, Toronto, Ontario, 2020-2021

- Successfully updated the companies old outdated website to modern design by incorporating upto markup and programming language.
- Maintain the content of the website as per clients requirements.

Live: https://www.abonpharma.com/

Customer Service Associate

TELEPERFORMANCE | Toronto, Ontario, 2018-2019

- Successfully organized and reviewed warranty claims by the customers.
- Elaborately explained to customers dit erent policies on warranties.

Associate Architect

REE ARCHITECTS | Dhaka, Bangladesh, 2015-2017

- Prepared scale drawings and architectural designs, using computeraided design or other tools.
- Created complex graphics and 3d modeling renderings, using independent judgment, creativity, and computer equipment.

Junior Architect

VISTAARA ARCHITECTS | Dhaka, Bangladesh, 2013-2015

- Successfully Illustrated architectural plans and designs as per the senior architects vision, using up to date architectural technology.
- Communicated successfully with other department for smooth operation of construction